<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Walkow</title>
    <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sam Walkow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:52:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://samwalkow.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 18:31:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samwalkow.github.io/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>. I am a PhD student in Informatics at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. I work with Dr. Matthew Turk in the Data Exploration Lab where we pursue research on open source scientific software development, data visualization and analytics, and software in education.
I am interested in understanding how users think about data, and how that internal representation of data changes as it is combined with scientific software to address research questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:52:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samwalkow.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>  . </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks and Posters</title>
      <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 17:41:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samwalkow.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>Talks Querying Data in yt - Domain Stories and Workflows Presented on December 11, 2020 at the 2020 RHytHM Event
I talk about the domain stories in depth with a focus on yt applications at the RHytHM: ResearcH using yt Highlights Meeting.
Check out the Slides.
Building a Sustainable Domain Knowledge Framework for Natural Science Software Tools Presented on April 1st, 2020 at the 2020 What is Information Conference
I presented on the findings from three domain stories of users implementing yt for astrophysics analysis at the What is Information conference online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 17:16:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samwalkow.github.io/blog/</guid>
      <description>I write about computer programing, learning how to code, and how people think about software.
  I re-mixed this project on Glitch, and worked on a small app to analyze some survey data about programming:
 https://www.hastac.org/blogs/samwalkow/2019/12/16/who-asks-computer-programming-questions-online    Lately I&#39;ve been reading a lot about learning how to program and tools like Blocky, and wrote about my experience with those tools:
 https://www.hastac.org/blogs/samwalkow/2019/09/23/building-blocks-computer-programming-literally    I had an amazing time at my first HASTAC conference!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://samwalkow.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 09:59:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samwalkow.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Ideology, Psychology, and Technology in Education January 2021 - In Progress
Starting in spring 2021, I will be investigating how ideology and psychology theory come together through EdTech and influence education users.
More information to come!
 Domain Stories - Astronomy and Beyond January 2019 - In Progress
This project is part of a larger effort to understand users mental model of data, and how that is applied when using scientific software to answer research questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>